

Ian Spangler, Creative Technologist

442 East 20th Street, New York, N.Y. 10009 H: 212-706-0022 / C: 917-495-0253 ian@ian-spangler.com www.ian-spangler.com www.linkedin.com/in/ianspangler

SUMMARY

MFA-graduate digital designer/ imagineer with 8+ years professional experience defining, visualizing and crafting custom websites, applications, and other user experiences for national clientele in entertainment, music, and publishing. Creative, technical, and managerial prowess with ability to effectively balance design and programming concerns while maximizing product-level innovation and results.

EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder, Chief Creative Technologist, The Imagine Film List *New York, N.Y. (Oct. 2012 — Present)*

Direct technology, information architecture, and interface design for the large-scale, user-generated entertainment website, iflist.com.

- Co-designed and developed, from scratch, the first version of the site for desktop users — from wireframes and user flows to page mockups to content strategy and database design to front and backend coding using a LAMP stack
- Devised a convenient signup/ login system that contributed to a 14-25% signup rate with over 100,000 users registered in nine months
- Defined and architected a unique set of modules and forms that spawned tens of thousands of user proposals and comments while fostering a consistent retention rate of 25-27% and bounce rate of 20-28%
- Guided a team of developers to roll out a feature-rich mobile site while optimizing backend infrastructure and administrative tools for content managers
- · Created detailed specs for new features and supervised production workflows
- · Translated high-level design and business strategy into practical and meaningful interactions

Interactive Designer, Townsquare Media New York, N.Y. (Oct. 2011 — Feb. 2013)

Designed user interfaces, advertisements, mini-games, and graphic components for national music and movie-news websites, local radio station websites, and a flagship mobile application.

- Developed detailed wireframes and user flows for mobile sites, audio players, and consumer deals website "Seize the Deal"
- · Designed illustrative site themes and backgrounds for desktop sites
- Created detailed mockups for new interfaces and features, covering full ranges of UI states and scenarios
- Dissected and revised a Wordpress theme picker UI to transition hundreds of sites to a responsive, mobile-friendly framework
- · Managed production of web templates and graphic assets such as logos

Interactive Developer/ Designer, True North Inc. New York, N.Y. (Jun. 2007 - Oct. 2011)

Built, maintained, and designed a variety of interactive, web-based products for an ad agency serving national clients such as Disney Channel, ABC, and Toys 'R Us.

- Worked with small teams of art directors, designers, and developers to create custom-coded websites and microsites, desktop applications, Facebook apps, banner ads, games, and Flash animations
- · Planned, led and managed execution of internal web applications from UI/UX planning through development, QA testing and launch
- · Mentored production artists in design implementation and coding
- Active usability advocate and key team member on 4 ECHO award-winning campaigns

Freelance Designer/ Developer, Sanborn Media Factory New York, N.Y. (May 2006 - Aug. 2006)

Contracted to design, hand-code, and update front-ends of marketing sites and emails for high-profile magazines and publishers including GQ, Architectural Digest, Bon Appetit, and Penguin.

Computer Instructor/ Consultant, Private Enterprise

New York, N.Y. (Apr. 2004 - Mar. 2006)

Independent contractor providing computer support, education, and troubleshooting.

EDUCATION

M.F.A. in Design & Technology, Parsons The New School for Design *New York, N.Y. (Aug. 2005 — May 2007)*

- · Core work in HCI/ interaction design and prototyping
- Elective studies in client & server-side programming, Flash/ Actionscript, game design, visual communication, and more
- · Overall GPA: 3.95/4.00

B.A. in Film, Vassar College Poughkeepsie, N.Y. (Sep. 1998 — May 2002)

- · Graduated Phi Beta Kappa with Honors
- · President of Vassar College Television

SKILLS

Software: Adobe CS6 (Photoshop, Illustrator, Flash, After Effects), Omnigraffle, Tower/ Github, Versions, Sublime Text

Languages: HTML5/ XHTML, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, AJAX, JSON, PHP, Twig, mySQL, Actionscript, XML, C/C++

Services: Amazon AWS, Google Analytics, Facebook/ Twitter/ Pinterest API's, Wikipedia API, YouTube API, Memcache, Wordpress, MailChimp, BrowserStack

Domains: ideation, wireframing, prototyping, information architecture, project management, usability testing, web development, SEO, visual design, illustration, 2D & 3D animation, video & sound editing

^{*} References plus additional experience and skills furnished upon request